Okay, so this is it.
Let the illusion begin.
Well before programming, let's look at what we want to happen as this will help us understand what
we need to code.
So dragging our road sprite, we wanted to come down like this, making it look like we're driving forward.
Then when it reaches the end, we want it to go back to the start, but do so perfectly so it looks
like nothing happened.
Well, to start off, let's just grab a when starts a forever and a change Y by ten we can quickly hit
play.
And yeah, that's the wrong way.
So let's make it a minus ten.
And well, that's pretty much what we want.
So now all we need to do is have the road go back up before it gets too low down.
So for this, all we need to do is.
Well, I'm not going to tell you just yet.
How about pausing the video and try and figure out how to make this perfect loop yourself so that the
road goes back up?
Come on, pause and give it a thought.
Well, let's have a look.
Firstly, we're going to need an if condition.
And what we want to check is the y position of our sprite.
Here we need to check if the y position is less than say -160.
So we can use this operator to see if y is less than -160.
Remember to check which way the arrow is pointing.
This way is less than, and this way is more than.
To help you remember this, just pay attention to the size at the start.
Here it is going from a size that is less than where it starts, and here is going from a size that
is greater than okay, now that you know that we can move our block inside our if and then inside our
forever loop.
Now all we need to do is change the position back.
So we just use a goto block set X to zero.
And for why?
To start off, we can just set it to 160.
Now clicking play, you can see this kind of works, but as you can also see, the loop is very off.
So this is where we need a bit of trial and error to get it perfect.
Now, the easiest way to get this is by grabbing to go to blocks.
The first we can set to -160.
As this is where we change it back.
And the next we can set to 160 which is this block.
Now first click on the first one, then our next one.
Well, you can see that the position is just a bit off.
So what needs to happen is we need to decrease our y a bit.
That's better, but still a bit off.
So again, a bit more.
And that looks better.
So as you can see, it's just a bit of trial and error.
And now, although our loop is good, you can see our costume isn't quite perfectly aligned.
So we can go back into the editor and try to make some micro adjustments.
And again, here you just need to keep fiddling until you get something that looks good.
Well, with that, we could change our Y values to this new one here.
And when we kick play once more.
Yeah, I think the results speak for themselves.
Also, although it looks good if we change from -160 to -150 and play the loop again, you'll see it
works out a bit better.
That, my friends, is what we call a proper illusion.
Obviously you can endlessly fiddle around to get it even more seamless, but for now that's looking
good.
And I know this has been a little bit of a tedious process, but trust me when I say this is a very
good skill to have.
And now we can start looking at coding the other sprites.